Hans Schnedlitz

Senior Ruby on Rails Engineer

About

I'm a Ruby on Rails Engineer specialized in operations and infrastructure. I have years of experience tuning performance, creating high-performing APIs and establishing continuous delivery pipelines.

On the side, I'm the organizer of Vienna.rb Ruby Meetup, do technical writing for AppSignal and am active in Open Source (Rails Mini Profiler, GraphQL Groups, and more).

Experience

Self-employed, 2024 - Present

Performance optimization & infrastructure migrations for various customers in the DACH region.

Meister, 2018 - 2023

Tech Lead for MeisterTask team. Lead migration to Kubernetes. Introduced Observability and OpenTelemetry. Heavy focus on APIs (GraphQL, REST), performance and infrastructure

Splendit IT-Consulting, 2017-2018

Developed Eclipse plugin for automated code refactoring. Streamlined internal processes & continuous integration using Docker & Jenkins.

Tricentis, 2013-2015)

Developed extensions for test automation in Java, C#, Delphi. Maintained WebsphereMQ and ActiveMQ integrations.

Skills

Backend

Ruby on Rails, MySQL, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, REST, Sidekiq

Infrastructure

Docker, OpenTelemetry, Kubernetes, Helm

Frontend

Hotwire, StimulusJS, React, HTML, CSS

Education

BSc Software Engineering

TU Wien (2015-2020)

Mathematics

TU Wien (2009-2013)

Contact

nansschnedlitz.com

\$\\$ +43 680 1212 783